[{"question":"What was the first Best Picture winner made entirely in color?","answers":["Gone With the Wind","How Green Was My Valley","Rebecca","The Wizard of Oz"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"Which actor from The Longest Yard (1974) joined the cast of Adam Sandler's 2005 remake?","answers":["Burt Reynolds","Bernadette Peters","Ray Nitschke","Richard Kiel"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"In which Arnold Schwarzenegger blockbuster does he say, \"I need your clothes, boots and your motorcycle?\"","answers":["Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991)","Batman & Robin (1997)","Eraser (1996)","True Lies (1994)"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"What brand of designer sunglasses experienced a 2000% increase in sales after Tom Cruise wore them in Risky Business?","answers":["Ray-Ban","Chanel","Gucci","Oakley"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"Which iconic building is not destroyed by aliens in Independence Day?","answers":["Chrysler Building","Capitol Records building","Empire State Building","The White House"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"In The Social Network, what role does the pop star turned actor Justin Timberlake play?","answers":["Napster co-founder Sean Parker","Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg","Harvard president Larry Summers","Microsoft chairman Bill Gates"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"Which 2010 release is based on a video game?","answers":["Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time","Clash of the Titans","Splice","The Last Airbender"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"Aldous Snow, the out-of-control rock star played by Russell Brand in Get Him to the Greek, first appeared in which comedy?","answers":["Forgetting Sarah Marshall","Funny People","Pineapple Express","Superbad"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"\"Dreams feel real while we're in them. It's only when we wake up that we realize something was actually strange.\" Name the character and 2010 movie.","answers":["Cobb (Leonardo DiCaprio), Inception","Dr. John Cawley (Ben Kingsley), Shutter Island","Mad Hatter (Johnny Depp), Alice in Wonderland","Mr. Han (Jackie Chan), The Karate Kid"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"Which Las Vegas hotel hosts the hard-partying groomsmen in The Hangover?","answers":["Caesars Palace","The Mirage","MGM Grand","The Venetian"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"Walk the Line recounts the turbulent life of which singer?","answers":["Johnny Cash","Bobby Darin","Bob Dylan","Ray Charles"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"Which Denzel Washington movie of the 00's earned him an Oscar?","answers":["Training Day","American Gangster","The Great Debaters","The Manchurian Candidate"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"\"With great power comes great responsibility.\" Which 00's superhero flick is this tagline from?","answers":["Spider-Man","Batman Begins","Iron Man","Superman Returns"],"difficulty":"1"},{"question":"Who is the oldest Best Actor nominee?","answers":["Richard Farnsworth","John Gielgud","Henry Fonda","Clint Eastwood"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Who was the first performer to win Oscars in both the lead and supporting categories?","answers":["Jack Lemmon","Gene Hackman","Jack Nicholson","Robert De Niro"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Before Robert Downey Jr., Shaquille O'Neal portrayed a weapons-maker turned superhero in what 1997 film?","answers":["Steel","Panther","Blade","The Meteor Man"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"What superhero film had its promotional trailer pulled after the September 11 attacks because it contained a shot of the Twin Towers?","answers":["Spider-Man","Daredevil","Hulk","X2"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"In Rudy (1993), the title character (Sean Astin) says, \"You're the only one who ever took me seriously.\" Who's he talking to?","answers":["His best friend","His teammate","His coach","His father"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"In Jerry Maguire (1996), what's the name of the team on which Rod Tidwell (Cuba Gooding Jr.) plays?","answers":["Arizona Cardinals","Dallas Cowboys","Oakland Raiders","St. Louis Rams"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Which movie coach tells his team, \"This is no democracy. It is a dictatorship. I am the law.\"","answers":["Coach Herman Boone in Remember the Titans","Coach Bud Kilmer in Varsity Blues","Coach Jimmy McGinty in The Replacements","Coach Ara Parseghian in Rudy"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"In which sun-drenched city does the young clownfish Nemo end up in a dentist's fish tank in Finding Nemo?","answers":["Sydney, Australia","Cape Town, South Africa","Honolulu, Hawaii","Rio de Janeiro, Brazil"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Isla Nubar, a fictional island that is the setting of Jurassic Park, lies off the west coast of which Latin American country?","answers":["Costa Rica","Argentina","Guatemala","Mexico"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"How old is Harry Potter when he enters Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry in Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone?","answers":["11","9","12","14"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"What glittery powder do the Weasleys use to transport themselves to Diagon Alley in Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets?","answers":["Floo powder","Belch powder","Bulbadox powder","Wartcap powder"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Which country does Liz Gilbert not visit during her yearlong quest in Eat Pray Love?","answers":["Greece","Bali","India","Italy"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Woody, Buzz, and the rest of Andy's toys are mistakenly delivered to which day-care center in Toy Story 3? ","answers":["Sunnyside","Ankle Biters","Rainbows","Li'l Beginnings"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"How many evil ex-boyfriends must Scott Pilgrim defeat before he can win over the girl of his dreams in Scott Pilgrim vs. the World?","answers":["7","5","1","11"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Which 2010 thriller is a remake?","answers":["Let Me In","Buried","The Ghost Writer","The Last Exorcism"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"An added scene after the end credits of Iron Man 2 introduced which new superhero?","answers":["Thor","Captain America","Green Lantern","Silver Surfer"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Which 2009 movie earned more than $400 million at the box office?","answers":["Transformers: Revenge of the Fallen","Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince","The Twilight Saga: New Moon","Watchmen"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Johnny Depp stars in Public Enemies as which infamous American outlaw?","answers":["John Dillinger","Jesse James","Al Capone","Machine Gun Kelly"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Which 2009 release does not star Sandra Bullock?","answers":["He's Just Not That Into You","All About Steve","The Blind Side","The Proposal"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"\"You will always be a child of two worlds, and fully capable of deciding your own destiny.\" Name the 2009 blockbuster.","answers":["Star Trek","Where The Wild Things Are","District 9","Avatar"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"How many Oscars did Peter Jackson's Lord of the Rings trilogy win?","answers":["17","11","15","26"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Name the fictional rock band at the center of Cameron Crowe's Almost Famous.","answers":["Stillwater","Mad River","Bandits","The Tribe"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Which Best Picture Oscar winner from the 00's is a remake?","answers":["The Departed","Crash","Gladiator","Million Dollar Baby"],"difficulty":"2"},{"question":"Who was the first woman to win Oscars for acting and writing?","answers":["Emma Thompson","Holly Hunter","Ruth Gordon","Shirley MacLaine"],"difficulty":"3"},{"question":"Which popular actor was originally cast as the whip-cracking adventurer Indiana Jones in Raiders of the Lost Ark?","answers":["Tom Selleck","Jack Nicholson","Nick Nolte","Steve Martin"],"difficulty":"3"},{"question":"Llewelyn Moss (Josh Brolin) discovers a satchel filled with how much drug money at the beginning of No Country for Old Men?","answers":["$2000000","$750000","$1000000","$5000000"],"difficulty":"3"}]